（真方ジン）レイツェル…。
Raetsel...
（レイツェル）そうよ…　レイツェルよ　ジン。
That's right, Jin. I'm Raetsel.
（エニグマ）全てのパズラーを　せん滅する。
To annihilate all puzzlers
as per my covenant with Makata Jin.
真方ジンとの盟約に従って…。
（フーダニット）俺のパズルが解けなきゃ
仲間同様…。
If you can't solve my puzzle, you'll end up just like your friends!
グァー。　フハハハハ！
（逆之上ギャモン）くっ…。
パズルで君を倒す。
To defeat you using puzzles.
ジンが何よりも憎み　嫌悪し
消滅を望んでいた…　パズルで！
Using the very puzzles Jin hated, detested, and tried to destroy!
You know nothing
We've gotta find the correct exit and get out of here, quick!
（大門カイト）早く正解のドアを
見つけて　ここを脱出しねえと！
Kaito...
カイト…。
ねえ　ジン。→
See, Jin.
ジンは　ネズミ　嫌いだったわよね。
Jin, you've always hated rats.
私はね…。
（指を鳴らす音）
But that's too bad... I love them.
大好き。
あいつが指を鳴らす度に
回転する像。
The statue rotates whenever she snaps her fingers.
それが　このパズル唯一の鍵だ。
That's the only hint in this puzzle.
What's does it mean then?
一体　どういう意味が…？
（指を鳴らす音）
そうか！　もし
像が回転するだけだったら→
I see!
If only the statue is rotating, the exit won't change.
正解のドアは
移動するはずがねえ！
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
でも…　そうじゃなかった。
But that wasn't it.
…って事は！
あっ　カイト！
Which means—
Kaito!
この像は　初めから
回転なんかしてなかったんだ。
The statue never rotated in the first place!
Huh?
It was the room rotating, not the statue.
回転していたのは
この部屋の方だったんだよ。
Every time she snapped her fingers, the doors swapped by one.
指が鳴る度に　正解のドアは
最初の地点から移動していたんだ。
レイツェルが　これまでに
指を鳴らした回数は　６回。
Raetsel's snapped her fingers six times already.
Which means this door leads to the exit!
つまり　今　出口に
つながっているのは…→
このドアだ！
何!?
行き止まり！
What?
A dead end?
Too bad! Wrong!
ざ～んねん！　ウフッ。　外れ～。
危ない！　カイト！
Watch out, Kaito!
I'm a Master Brain, Whodunit.
（フーダニット）俺は　マスターブレインのフーダニット。
初めに　超重要なお知らせだ。
Let me tell you something quite important.
Try running away! You'll never solve a puzzle again!
逃げたりなんかしてみろ。
お前ら　もう二度と
パズルが解けなくなるよ！
はあ？　訳分かんねえ事
言ってんじゃねえぞ！
You're not making any sense, moron!
グヘッ。　悪魔がお前らを
食っちまうよ～！　ヒャーッハッハッハ！
A demon's gonna eat y'all!
I totally get it. How fucking broken you are, that is.
てめえが　どんだけ
ぶっ壊れてるのか→
よ～く分かったぜ。
You got the fight you wanted!
そのケンカ　買った！
I'll make sure to break you even more!
てめえは
俺様が全力で　ぶっ潰す！
あっ…　ルーク!?
Rook!
ルーク君！
大丈夫。　かすり傷だよ。
I'm fine. It's just a flesh wound.
くっ…。　レイツェル！
Raetsel!
次が　ラストチャンス。
今度　間違えたら→
The next time is your last chance!
If you get it wrong, you're gonna die!
本当に死ぬわよ。
くっ…。
心の声
どういう事だ？
像が回転してると見せかけて→
What's going on?
I thought that the room rotating instead of the statue was the key to this puzzle.
回転していたのは部屋。
それが　パズルの鍵のはずなのに…。→
Did I miss something?
俺は　何かを
見落としているのか…？
この程度のパズルも解けないなんて→
You can't even solve a puzzle like this?
Did you learn nothing from Jin at all?
君　ジンから何も学ばなかったの？
From Jin?
ジンから!?
ジンから　俺が学んだ事
それは…。
Jin taught me to...
回想
（ジン）カイト　解いてやれ。
自由にしてやれ　パズルを…。
Kaito! Solve them. Set them free.
出会ったパズルは　必ず解く！
I'll solve every puzzle I come across.
ウフッ。
There's no puzzle I can't solve!
俺に解けないパズルは　ねえ！
The room definitely rotated.
確かに　部屋は回転していた。
だが　像も回転していた。
But so did the statue.
She split their movements to her left and right hands.
あいつは　その２つの操作を→
右手と左手で
区別して行っていたんだ。
From that, there are five possible answers.
そこから導き出される
正解の可能性は　５つ。
The problem is remembering how many times she snapped her fingers on each hand
問題は　レイツェルが　右手と左手で
指を何回　鳴らしたか。
and figuring out which hand controls the statue and which controls the room.
そして　右と左の
どちらが部屋で　どちらが像か…。
カイト！
Kaito!
回数なら　私　覚えてるよ。
I remember the numbers.
右と左が　それぞれ３回ずつ。
She's snapped both her left and right hands 3 times each.
うん！
（ノノハ　ルーク）うん！
行こう　ルーク　ノノハ！
Let's go, Rook, Nonoha!
Yeah!
心の声
部屋と像は　それぞれ
３回ずつ回転した。→
Both the room and statue rotated three times.
つまり
今　正解の出口があるのは…。
Which means I know where the exit is.
フン。
（ジン）そうか。
I see.
このパズルは…。
So this puzzle was...
このドアだ。
It's this door!
よっしゃ！
All right!
Rook?
ルーク。
大丈夫か？　ルーク。
ああ。
Are you okay, Rook?
（レイツェル）ウフフフッ　アハハハ！
やっぱり覚えててくれたんだ！→
I knew you'd remember! It was a puzzle we made together!
一緒に作った　パズルの事。
そんな気がしたんだ。
あのパズルは　僕が…。
That's how it felt. I felt like I made it.
何だって!?
What?
おい！　お前
一体　ジンと　どういう…。
How are you two related?
Jin's... remembered the past.
ジ～ン～は～！
ジンは　昔の事を
思い出してくれたわ。→
君たちが　どうあがいても
駄目だったのに。
See, you couldn't do that no matter how hard you tried.
ジン。　この世界から　全てのパズラーを
せん滅するという　ジンの願い→
I'll be sure to fulfill your wish of annihilating all puzzlers from this world, Jin.
私が　かなえてあげるわ。
ふざけるな！
Get real!
ジンが　そんな事　言うわけねえ！
Jin would never say that!
（レイツェル）何よ。　ジンが
パズルを愛していたとでも言うの？
Huh? You're saying Jin liked puzzles?
そうだ。　ジンは
誰よりも　パズルを愛していた！
That's right!
He loved puzzles more than anyone!
へえ～…　ウフフフフ。
やっぱり　君
ジンの事　何も知らないんだ。
You really know nothing about him.
なっ…。
（レイツェル）さあ　ジン　行きましょ。
Let's go, Jin.
Wait! Where are you going?
待て！　おい　どこへ!?
君も来る？
Wanna come?
教えてあげるわ。　本当のジンを。
I'll show you the real Jin.
（ビショップ）一介の少女が　なぜ
このような　プライベートジェットを…。
Why would a random girl have a private jet like this?
（ルーク）彼女の背後には　どうやら
とてつもない闇がありそうだ。
I guess she has a hidden darkness about her.
あっ…
何なの!?　この　でっかい船！
What's with this huge ship?!
That's the seal of the Republic of Amguinea.
（ビショップ）
あれは…　アムギーネ共和国の紋章。
この船は　アムギーネ共和国の
所有物という事か。
That would mean this is a ship of Amguinea.
Don't worry.
安心して。　この船では
私は自由に行動できるの。→
On this ship, I can do whatever I want.
そういう契約になってるから。
That's how my contract works.
「ジンは　パズルを愛していた」。→
"Jin loved puzzles."
君　そう言いたいのよね？
ああ。
You want to prove that, right?
Yeah.
これが事実よ。
Well, these are facts.
What?
何だよ…　何なんだよ　これは!?
What's this?
（レイツェル）マスターブレインによって倒され
再起不能になった　パズラーたちよ。
They are puzzlers damaged beyond repair after being defeated by the Master Brains.
マスターブレイン？
（レイツェル）ジン。
Master Brains?
You really know nothing about Jin at all.
彼　何も分かってないわ。　ウフフフ。
今　マスターブレインたちは
世界中で　パズラーを狩ってるわ。
The Master Brains are out there hunting puzzlers as we speak.
ジンの理想を実現させるために。
They work to make Jin's dream a reality.
Guys...
みんな！
あいつら…　何を…？
What are they doing?
彼らの愛する　パズルで
パズラーを　せん滅する。
Destroy the puzzles they love. Destroy the puzzlers.
そうよね？　ジン。
Right, Jin?
（レイツェル）見てて。　あなたの憎んだ
パズルの恐ろしさを…。
Just look at how dreadful the puzzles you hated can be.
Let's start with some good news.
（フーダニット）
ここで　お前らに　グッドニュースだ。
大門カイトは
無事　パズルを解放したらしいぜ。
Daimon Kaito broke free from the puzzle he was trapped in.
フン！　やっぱりな。
I knew it!
（アナ・グラム）ばんざ～い！
あだ～！
Hurray!
フフッ。　では　次に…　バッドニュースだ～！
Next is the bad news!
（キュービック・Ｇ）うわ～！
危ねえ！　逃げろ！
Run!
うわわわ…
うわ～！
どわっ！
What?! Run!
（ギャモン）何!?　逃げろ！
（ギャモン）どっ…　どぁ～！
（キュービック　アナ）あ～！
痛ててて…。　あっ!?
Iwashimizu!
イワシミズ君！
Damn you, bastard! What are you doing?!
（ギャモン）てめえ！　何のまねだ!?
Welcome to my puzzle!
ようこそ　俺のパズルへ！→
あらかじめ置かれた立方体を
手がかりに→
Use the cubes on the field you were originally put on as a hint
パズルボードの全ての穴を
立方体で埋めろ。→
to fill all the holes with cubes!
You can use seven colors consisting of red, blue, yellow, purple, orange, green, and black.
使われている色は
赤　青　黄　紫　オレンジ　緑　黒の７色。
制限時間は　１０分。→
You have ten minutes.
１０分過ぎたら　床に電流が流れて
お前らは…。
If you can't do it in time, the floor will be electrocuted, and you'll go—
（フーダニット）ヒャーッハッハッハ！
Fuck yourself! No one cares about your blabber!
（ギャモン）うっせえ！
おしゃべり勘違い野郎！
こんなパズル　俺一人で十分だ。
２人を出しやがれ。
I can handle this puzzle by myself.
Let the other two out.
逆之上ギャモン！
Sakanoue Gammon! 750,000 bucks.
えっ？
（フーダニット）７５万ドル。
えっ…　くれんの？
キュービック・Ｇ！　６５万ドル。
Cubic Galois! 650,000 bucks.
（フーダニット）アナ・グラム！　９０万ドル！
Ana Gram! 900,000 bucks.
ほえ？
てめえ！　一体　何　言ってやがる!?
What the fuck are you even talking about?!
これが　お前ら　ファイ・ブレインの
子供たちに懸けられた賞金だ。
Those are the bounties for you children of the Phi Brain.
What? I'm the lowest?
（キュービック）え～！　僕が一番低いの？
（アナ）やった～！
Yay! I'm the highest!
アナ　１番！
貸せ。
Gimme!
Wait, why am I lower than Ana?!
どうして　俺が
アナより低いんだよ!?
That totals 2.3 million dollars.
合計　２３０万ドル。
According to the contract, Enigma will pay me if I take you guys out.
お前らを倒したら
エニグマが払うって契約だ。
By the way, Daimon Kaito's ten million dollars by himself!
ちなみに　大門カイトは
１，０００万ドルだ！
え～！　１，０００万ドル!?
Ten million dollars?!
Oh? That's a good deal.
（ギャモン）
そうか…　そりゃ　いい商売だな。
ヘヘヘ…　１，０００万　１，０００万…。
Ten million? Oh, so ten million?
（フーダニット）やれやれ…
俺も　できる事なら→
Man, I would've loved to go hunt him too if I could.
大門カイトを
狩りにいきたかったぜ。→
賞金１，０００万ドルに比べりゃ
お前ら３人を始末するなんて→
Compared to a ten milion bounty, taking you guys out is basically volunteer work.
ボランティアみたいなもんだからなぁ。
んだと!?　おらぁ！
ザケんじゃねえ！
What was that?!
Who are you fuckin' with?! I'll butcher you, clown!
てめえは
俺が絶対に潰してやる！→
俺には　２，０００万ドルの価値が
あるって事を証明してやるぜ！→
I'll show you I'm worth twenty million!
おい！　てめえ　聞いてんのか!?
Hey! Are you even listening?
ハッ！　せいぜい頑張るんだな
７５万ドル。
Good luck there, 750k.
それでは…　パズルタイム　スタート！
It's puzzle time then!
このパズルは
色の法則に支配されている。→
This puzzle's ruled by the colors.
その法則さえ見抜けりゃ
こっちの勝ちだ。
If I can find the rule behind the colors, then we've got it.
Is this some kind of color sudoku?
ひょっとして
これは…　色のナンプレか！
もし　そうなら
組み合わせは　２，６００万以上だ。
But then there are over 2600 possible combinations.
んなもん
１０分で解けるはずねえだろ！
No way we could solve that in ten minutes!
Says the 750k.
（フーダニット）さすがは　７５万。
早くも敗北宣言か～？
Giving up already?
うっせえ
この　おしゃべり勘違い野郎！
Shut up, you chatterbox bastard!
心の声
（ギャモン）くそっ…　一体
どうやって解きゃいいんだ？
Crap. How am I supposed to solve this?
（ビショップ）なんという難解な…。
That sure looks difficult.
私には　手がかりすら見えません。
みんな…。
I don't even see any hints.
Guys...
ジン　よく見て。→
Just look, Jin.
そして　思い出して。
パズルに対する憎しみを…。
And remember how you hated puzzles.
（フーダニット）
ほらほら　６５万ドルと　９０万ドルも
手伝ってやったらどうだ？
Come on! Help him, 650k and 900k!
まあ　３人でかかったところで→
Not that you could solve a Master Brain's puzzle, even if the three of you worked together.
マスターブレインの俺様のパズルは
解けやしないがな。
もう　何なんだよ!?
マスターブレインって。
Oh, come on! What even is a Master Brain?
フン。　真方ジンと盟約を結んだ
ファイ・ブレインを超える者たちだ。
People beyond the Phi Brain who made contracts with Makata Jin!
（ギャモン）チッ。　また　真方ジンかよ。
Makata Jin again?
Despise puzzles and puzzlers.
（フーダニット）パズルとパズラーを憎み
その象徴的な存在である→
Annihilate the pinnacle of puzzlers, the children of the Phi Brain.
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちを
せん滅する。
それが　真方ジンの考えなんだよ。
That's Makata Jin's plan.
See?
ほ～ら。
Gammon, this won't do.
ギャモン　このままじゃ
マズいよ。
んなこたぁ　分かってる！
I know that!
キュー太郎　お前は
このパズル　どう見る？
Cubie, what do you see here?
I'm not very good at artsy stuff.
（キュービック）僕は　こういうアート系
苦手だからな…。
そうだ　アナは？
Oh, right. What about Ana?
あれっ…　アナ!?
Huh? Ana?
（アナ）アナが思うに～。
ん？
I think... I like this box the most!
この箱が一番好き～！
駄目だ　こりゃ。
This is hopeless.
おやおや
それで終わりか？　７５万ドル。
Is that it, 750k?
（ギャモン）てめえ！
人を賞金で呼ぶんじゃねえ！
Stop calling people by some bounty!
In three more minutes, I'll get 2.3 million fried!
あと３分で
合計２３０万ドルが→
こんがり焼き上がるぜ。
ヒャーハハハ！
うっせえ！　なら　こっちも
３分以内に→
Fuck you! I'll wipe that damn annoying grin off your face in three minutes then!
Roasted black!
てめえのムカつく笑いを
消してやるぜ！
ヒャッハーハハ！　やれるもんなら
やってみやがれ　この７５万ドル！
Good luck trying, 750k!
心の声
（ギャモン）くっ…。　これらの色には
何か意味があるはずだ。→
The colors must have some meaning.
If only I knew what that was...
それさえ分かれば…。
（アナ）アナ　分かった～！
心の声
（ギャモン）何!?
I got it!
What?!
Red is red!
赤は　レッド！
タコスケが！　この忙しい時に
何　言ってんだよ！
おぉ…。
Are you nuts? We don't have time for this!
待って！
もしかして　それ→
Wait a moment!
Does he mean we should think about the colors in English?
色を英語で表記するって
事じゃない？
（ギャモン）
赤は　「ＲＥＤ」。　黄色は　「ＹＥＬＬＯＷ」。→
That's red.
And that's yellow.
それぞれ英語表記した時の
字数を考えると→
Considering the English words for the colors,
they can all be converted to numbers.
色が数字に変化する。
そういう事だな？
アナ。
ほえ？
Is that it, Ana?
（ギャモン）という事は　これは…。
But that means—
魔方陣だ！
縦横　各列
数字の合計を出して→
It's a magic square!
Horizontal, vertical, and diagonal must all have the same total.
パズルに　はめ込みゃいいのか。
急ごう　ギャモン。
Let's hurry, Gammon!
Yeah!
（フーダニット）まさか…　このパズルの
法則が分かったとでもいうのか？
No way...
They found out the rule for this puzzle?
（ギャモン）ぬぉっし…。
ウハハハハ！　時間切れだ！→
Time's up!
いいとこまで　いったが
これで　ジ・エンドだぜ！
You were close, but now you're fried!
ギャモン！　もう時間が…。
Gammon! Time's up!
心配　要らねえ！
No worries!
そいつを　こっちへ投げろ！
（アナ　キュービック）え～!?
Throw that one over here!
急げ～！
Just do it!
（アナ　キュービック）ギャモーン！
Gammon!
ど～らっしゃぁ！
どぅっ！　これで　ラスト！
There it goes! The last one!
（アナ　キュービック）あ…　あ～！
ま…　まさか…。
No way...
俺の勝ちだ！
I win.
（アナ　キュービック）やった～！→
We did it!
Gammon won!
ギャモンが勝った　ギャモンが勝った
ギャモンが勝った…。
あれだけのパズルを
全て　頭の中だけで解いただと？
He solved the whole puzzle in his head?!
No way...
そんな…　たかが　７５万ドルに
この俺が負けるなんて…。
How could I lose to a mere 750k?!
（アナ　キュービック　イワシミズ君）
ギャモンが勝った　ギャモンが勝った…。
But I couldn't win alone.
心の声
（ギャモン）だが　俺一人じゃ
勝てなかった…。
やった～！
They did it!
どうだ　俺たちの勝ちだ！
We won!
そうね。　でも…。
That's right.
But...
How dreadful.
恐ろしい。
Maybe puzzles shouldn't exist after all.
やっぱり　パズルは存在しては
ならないのかもしれない。
ジン…。
Jin...
ほら　やっぱり。→
See?
記憶を失っても　ジンの　パズルを憎む
気持ちは変わらないのよ。
Even after losing his memories, Jin still hates puzzles.
ジン！
Jin!
But you won this time.
でも　確かに
今回は　君の勝ちね。→
You can have Jin for now.
いいわ。　ジンは預けておく。
ジンの記憶を取り戻すよう
努力してみたら？
Why not try harder to retrieve his memories?
Really? Even in England the villains called upon Jin's name?
（軸川ソウジ）そうですか…。
イギリスでも　ジンさんの名のもとに
新たなる刺客が…。
ＰＯＧの電子ライブラリーにも→
I found high-priority entries about him in the POG library as well.
ジンさんを要注意人物とする
データが存在しました。
考えてみれば　僕は　ジンの全てを
知っているわけじゃないんだ。
Now that I think about it, it's not like I know everything about him.
教えてくれませんか？
ジンの過去に何があったのか…。
Would you tell us
what's hidden in Jin's past?
（解道バロン）ピタゴラス伯爵と戦うために
世界を旅していたジンには→
Jin traveled the world in preparation for his fight with Count Pythagoras.
私も知らない
空白の１年がありました。→
There was a year where even I didn't know anything.
There is no one who knows what he did during that time.
その間　ジンが何をしていたのか
知る者は誰もいないのです。
ついに始まったね
私たちの戦いが…。
Our fight has finally begun.
As per our contract, I want you to put forth your best effort in defeating Daimon Kaito.
契約どおり　今後も
大門カイトを倒すために→
力を注いでほしい。→
That is to fulfill Jin's dream as well.
ジンの夢を　かなえるためにも…。
I'll go to Root Academy.
私　√学園に行くわ。
どうして!?
行きたいから。
Why?!
Because I want to.
やれやれ…　困った子猫だ。
Oh, my.
What a willful little kitten.
Preview